JOSHUA ROCHOTTE, MI, A-CSPO

Phone: (732) 406-1929 • joshjrochotte@gmail.com • LinkedIn.com/in/joshrochotte

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A dedicated and passionate product manager serving the life sciences industry for the past 4 years. Experience in leading teams to deliver highly functional, data science focused SAAS products and wearing many hats. Looking to secure a role in product focused data analysis or product management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MEDIDATA SOLUTIONS

Product Manager, Digital Oversight

Mar 2021 to Present

- Developed detailed roadmaps for virtual monitoring and data science applications
- Lead cross platform integration effort to unite applications and user workflow
- Promoted within 12 months due to strong performance and organizational impact

Product Owner, RBQM

Apr 2020 to Mar 2021

- Lead 3 global teams in the development of microservice analytics, metrics configuration and data review solutions, releasing new products every 3 months
- Efforts included product strategy, SCRUM practice, detailed requirements and mentorship of other Product Owners as a BA/PO mentor
- Passionate Encore Award received Jan 2021 for exemplified focus on company ideals

Implementation Consultant

Jul 2017 to Apr 2020

- Implementation of Medidata Clinical Cloud Software for 20+ Clients
- Provided study design, consultation, training and data focused error resolution to drive customer success across indications and market segments in Risk Based Quality Monitoring and Electronic Data Capture

EDUCATION

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

2017-2018

Master of Information, Data Science | Technology, Information and Management

- Research Project: Socially Influenced Cooperation in Competitive Scenarios Online
- Beta Phi Mu, International LIS Honor Society

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

2013-2017

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology | Bachelor of Arts Information Technology and Informatics

- Specialization in Game Design and Innovation
- Deans List

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- Certifications: Google Data Analytics (2021), Product Manager Certificate (2021), A-CSPO (2021), Mini MBA Biopharma Innovation (2017), Medidata Rave Study Builder/Admin (2017)
- Programming: Python, R, SQL, Java, C#, HTML/CSS/JS
- **Applications**: Microsoft Office 365, Axure, IndigoDesign, Balsamiq, JustInMind, Tableau, JIRA, Confluence, Lucidchart, AHA, Draw.IO, AWS, Slack, Salesforce, Trello
- Skills: Advanced Data Analytics, Business Intelligence, Agile Development, UI/UX Design, Project Management, Workflow Design, Research and Information Management, Risk Based Quality Management, Product Roadmaps, Relationship Management, Database Management

PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED LECTURES

| "Preparing for ICH E6 (R3) Good Clinical Practice Changes" Xtalks | Jun 2021 |
|---|---------------------|
| "Medidata Cloud Powers Clinical Trials of the Future" US FDA | Aug 2020 |
| "Big Data and Healthcare" Rutgers University | Apr 2018 |
| PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS | |
| New York Academy of Sciences | Jul 2021 to Present |
| AIPMM | Apr 2021 to Present |
| RUSCIAA | Jan 2021 to Present |
| Beta Phi Mu, Omicron Chapter | Apr 2020 to Present |
| Scrum Alliance | Mar 2020 to Present |
| PhUSE | Jan 2019 to Present |
| Project Management Institute | Jan 2018 to Present |
| OTHER | |

Data Science Passion Projects Computer and Console Gamer Avid Popular Science Reader Classically Trained Vocalist Amateur Cook